Jordi Noguera

jordinoguera83@gmail.com • jordinl.com • Github: jordinl83

Location: Barcelona

I'm a Full-Stack Software Engineer specializing in Ruby on Rails. I like clean simple well-tested code. Use RSpec and Jasmine to make sure my code works properly. Have experience in Agile methodologies such as Extreme Programming and Scrum. Very analytical, pragmatic and with a critical mind. I take pride in what I do and like going the extra mile. That could be doing some refactor when working on a story even if it's not strictly required to leave the codebase better than how I found it. Or trying to improve the UI to make it more pleasing. I understand that there is a lot more to software engineering than writing good code, good communication is equally important.

Skills:

Heroku Ruby and Rails

RSpec Python/Django HTML/HAML/SLIM AngularJs CSS/SASS/SCSS Backbone ReactJs CoffeeScript

Google App Engine *i*Ouerv

Mysql, SQLite, Postgres Sinatra Git **NodeJS**

Bash Amazon EC2 & S3

Work experience:

Feb 2016 – Present: **Spreemo** Freelance Software Engineer Remote

Working as part of a 6 people engineering team.

Rewriting PHP app into Ruby on Rails app released on February 2017.

Implementing end to end features (Ruby on Rails, jQuery, Slim, SCSS, MySQL).

Fixing performance issues – mostly slow queries or libraries implemented in a less than optimal way. Code review other engineers' work.

Give feedback to management on how to improve processes.

Freelance Software Engineer Remote Feb 2016 – Present: **Toptal**

Working for Toptal clients (only Spreemo as of today).

July 2014 – July 2015: Originate Inc Software Engineer New York

replay.io: Led Ruby on Rails team of 4 (Ruby on Rails, Slim, Sass, CoffeeScript). Angie's List: worked on front-end team for a React/Scala project.

Feb. 2012 – July 2014: **Pivotal Labs Software Engineer** San Francisco

CloudFoundry buildpacks: Forks of the Heroku's buildpacks that work on Cloudfoundry both on environments with and without internet. Examples of such buildpacks are Ruby and NodeJS. Also, developed tools to test that pushed apps work.

Pivotal Web Services console: Web UI to manage organizations inside Cloudfoundry built in Rails. RPX Portal: Implemented new features for the member's site of RPX.

Feb. 2011 – Oct. 2011: Freelance **Software Engineer** London

Python/django developer for Potato, working with Google's creative lab. Ruby Developer in Test at BBC's Future Media department.

Sept. 2010 – Dec. 2010: Headshift Ltd Software Engineer London

Feb. 2010 – Sept. 2010: **Tinderfields Ltd Software Engineer** London

July 2008 – July 2009: Indra Sistemas SA ABAP developer Barcelona

Side projects:

<u>operating_hours</u>: Ruby gem that efficiently calculates business time between two arbitrary date/times. See technical explanation <u>here</u>.

<u>HN Hiring</u>: Sinatra app running on Heroku that finds every month the "Who's hiring?" post on Hacker News.

Education:

September 01 – July 08: Degree in mathematics

Facultat de Matemàtiques i Estadística – Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (Spain) School of Mathematics and Statistics – The University of Sheffield (United Kingdom)